<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>PBL3 Group H</title>
    <link>https://xknt21.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on PBL3 Group H</description>
    <image>
      <title>PBL3 Group H</title>
      <url>https://xknt21.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://xknt21.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 01:06:59 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://xknt21.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[Group Documentation] May 13 2025</title>
      <link>https://xknt21.github.io/contents/may13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 01:06:59 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xknt21.github.io/contents/may13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary-of-activities&#34;&gt;Summary of Activities&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 13, our team focused on two major tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finalizing the interview questions for animal shelters and organizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mapping responsibilities and categorizing non-functional requirements (NFRs) for each team member, aligned with key stakeholders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;interview-question-design--animal-shelter-staff&#34;&gt;Interview Question Design – Animal Shelter Staff&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We brainstormed and refined a comprehensive list of questions to ask shelter staff in our upcoming interviews. These questions aim to deepen our understanding of real-world workflows, adoption procedures, and the shelter’s technical readiness to collaborate with our system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Group Documentation] May 6 2025</title>
      <link>https://xknt21.github.io/contents/may6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 01:06:59 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xknt21.github.io/contents/may6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary-of-activities&#34;&gt;Summary of Activities&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 6, our group focused on clarifying key system behaviors and preparing in-depth technical questions for our upcoming consultation with the professor. This work session was dedicated to translating our conceptual design into more concrete technical concerns, especially related to cat image handling, recognition, and re-identification processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;technical-planning-and-discussion&#34;&gt;Technical Planning and Discussion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discussed the expected photo upload process from general users, particularly from smartphones. While the feature itself was already listed as a requirement, we focused on exploring the technical details and potential user behaviors.
We identified the need to accept .jpg images from mobile users and started researching what image formats would be optimal for internal processing and model input. We agreed to seek expert input on whether conversion to other formats (e.g., .webp, .tiff) is recommended for performance or quality reasons.
We talked about challenges users might introduce, such as blurry images or inconsistent angles, and decided to ask about data pre-processing techniques to handle these cases effectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Group Documentation] April 24 2025</title>
      <link>https://xknt21.github.io/contents/apr24/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 01:06:59 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xknt21.github.io/contents/apr24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;smart-re-identification-application-for-stray-cats-post-snr-program&#34;&gt;Smart Re-Identification Application for Stray Cats Post-SNR Program&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;problem-elicitation--background&#34;&gt;Problem Elicitation / Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Urban animal shelters, particularly in regions like Taiwan, are heavily burdened and face legal or ethical restrictions against euthanizing animals. Following the Shelter-Neuter-Return (SNR) program, many cats are released back into the urban environment without systematic tracking, making it difficult to monitor their wellbeing or promote their adoption.&lt;br&gt;
There is a growing societal need for a solution that maintains a connection with these cats after their return, fostering animal welfare and enabling post-release care and adoption opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Group Documentation] April 22 2025</title>
      <link>https://xknt21.github.io/contents/apr22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 01:06:59 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xknt21.github.io/contents/apr22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;recognition-application-for-cats-after-snr-program&#34;&gt;Recognition Application for Cats after SNR Program&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;problem-statement&#34;&gt;Problem Statement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Urban animal shelters in many regions—such as Taiwan—are overburdened and face legal or ethical restrictions against euthanizing animals. As a result, many cats undergo SNR (Shelter, Neuter, Return) programs and are returned to city streets. Post-release, shelters lose track of these cats, making it difficult to monitor their health or facilitate potential adoptions. There&amp;rsquo;s a need for a data-driven system that allows society to stay connected to these animals, even after release.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Group Documentation] April 17 2025</title>
      <link>https://xknt21.github.io/contents/apr17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 01:06:59 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xknt21.github.io/contents/apr17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;citizen-based-participatory-budget-system-general-idea-for-now-we-have-a-few-ideas-for-data-processing-but-dont-know-which-one-to-choose&#34;&gt;Citizen-Based Participatory Budget System (general idea for now, we have a few ideas for data processing, but don’t know which one to choose)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;problem-statement&#34;&gt;Problem Statement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participatory budgeting (PB) empowers citizens to influence how public funds are allocated. However, challenges persist in ensuring fairness, transparency, and effective data utilization within these processes. Traditional methods may not adequately capture diverse community needs or leverage data-driven insights for optimal decision-making.​&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-acquisition&#34;&gt;Data Acquisition&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sources of Data:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presentation</title>
      <link>https://xknt21.github.io/presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 14:35:02 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xknt21.github.io/presentation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>System Design Document</title>
      <link>https://xknt21.github.io/system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 14:34:31 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xknt21.github.io/system/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>System Architecture</title>
      <link>https://xknt21.github.io/architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 14:34:06 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xknt21.github.io/architecture/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Group Documentation] April 15 2025</title>
      <link>https://xknt21.github.io/contents/apr15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 01:06:59 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xknt21.github.io/contents/apr15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ideas&#34;&gt;Ideas:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;toilet-finder-app&#34;&gt;Toilet Finder App&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helps users find nearby public restrooms. real-time crowd data, wheelchair accessibility, user reviews, location maps, and elevator info.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;parking-finder-app&#34;&gt;Parking Finder App&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It shows available parking spaces near sightseeing spots. real-time availability, price comparison, distance to destination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;community-feedback-participatory-budgetary-system&#34;&gt;Community feedback participatory budgetary system&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crowd sourcing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use geolocation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitor progress, suggest, discuss, vote etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine learning based rating system -&amp;gt; Agree or Disagree -&amp;gt; Motivates their transparency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;citizen-based-participatory-budgeting-system&#34;&gt;Citizen Based Participatory Budgeting System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Sets from Government website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gather feedbacks from Citizens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze feedback to improve the quality and motivate their transparency by being monitored&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;smart-food-scanner-a-personalised-ingredient-detection-app&#34;&gt;Smart Food Scanner: A Personalised Ingredient Detection App&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many international students and residents in Japan, including those who follow halal, vegetarian, vegan diets, or have specific food allergies, often face difficulties identifying suitable food options in convenience stores due to language barriers and unclear ingredient labelling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Group Documentation] April 11 2025</title>
      <link>https://xknt21.github.io/contents/apr11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 01:06:59 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xknt21.github.io/contents/apr11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ideas&#34;&gt;Ideas:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;highway-route-optimization&#34;&gt;Highway Route Optimization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would optimize the route across an expressway for vehicles to avoid traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;low-light-area-detectors&#34;&gt;Low-Light Area Detectors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use location of areas that are not lit up during the night to advise the government where to install street-lighting systems to improve nighttime visibility and increase safety of such low-light areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;urban-shadow-tracker&#34;&gt;Urban Shadow-Tracker&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detects public areas with too much and too less shade to predict and provide recommendations for the government to plant trees and install solar panels to reduce public over-exposure to solar radiation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Group Documentation] April 8 2025</title>
      <link>https://xknt21.github.io/contents/apr8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 01:06:59 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xknt21.github.io/contents/apr8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ideas&#34;&gt;Ideas:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;toilet-finder-application&#34;&gt;Toilet Finder Application&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a smart app feature designed to help users easily and effectively find public toilets in their environment. It&amp;rsquo;s especially helpful for those with special needs, such as the disabled or even clean and accessible toilet hunters. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rush Hour Detection:&lt;/strong&gt;  The application cross-checks the time and location information to find out how busy certain restrooms are. At rush hour, it will suggest less busy ones around so the users don&amp;rsquo;t have to wait.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Proposal</title>
      <link>https://xknt21.github.io/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xknt21.github.io/project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;smart-re-identification-application-for-stray-cats-post-snr-program&#34;&gt;Smart Re-Identification Application for Stray Cats Post-SNR Program&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project aims to develop an application capable of re-identifying stray cats that have been released following Shelter-Neuter-Return (SNR) programs. By capturing and uploading an image of a cat, users will be able to retrieve associated shelter records if the cat had previously been housed.&lt;br&gt;
The system primarily addresses challenges related to post-shelter adoption by enabling potential adopters to determine the adoption status of stray cats outside the shelter environment.&lt;br&gt;
Additionally, it offers broader support for stray cat population management and monitoring initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Requirements Specification</title>
      <link>https://xknt21.github.io/requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xknt21.github.io/requirements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;preface&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preface&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;version-history&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version History&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Version&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Date&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;1.0&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;April 28, 2025&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Finished the initial project proposal with the goal of streamlining and assisting the adoption process of stray cats.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;1.1&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;May 26, 2025&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Adjusted system structure, goal, and certain features based on interviews conducted with stakeholders. Project now focuses more on preventing hospitals from doing redundant checkups on stray cats. Completed requirements specification.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;document-conventions&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Document Conventions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key words “MUST”, “MUST NOT”, “REQUIRED”, “SHALL”, “SHALL NOT”, “SHOULD”, “SHOULD NOT”, “RECOMMENDED”, “MAY”, and “OPTIONAL” in this document are to be interpreted as described in &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc2119&#34;&gt;RFC 2119&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
